在上一集里
Previously on Transformers: Prime
由于领导模块的力量不再护佑他
With the power of the Matrix no longer within him...
理所当然的 他回到了成为领袖之前的状态：
It would stand to reason that Optimus has reverted to his pre-Prime state.
一个高频信号…
A high-frequency signal...
内含一个加密的信息
With an embedded message.
擎天柱在哪儿？
Where is Optimus?
除非你知道威震天把他的太空桥藏在何处…
Unless you know where Megatron is hiding his Space-bridge...
太空…桥！
Space... bridge!
…他们在没有我指导的情况下完成了？！
... They actually finished building it without my supervision?!
一旦我们控制了太空桥 就叫杰克过来
Once we secure the Space-bridge we'll send for Jack.
你们三个还要撑足够长的时间
You three need to hold it long enough for Jack and me
直到我和杰克从塞博特恩回来
to get to Cybertron and back.
我怎么可能是擎天柱？
How could I possibly be "Optimus Prime"?
魔力神球的真实位置早就被神话跟谣传歪曲了 杰克
Vector Sigma's true location is shrouded in myth and rumor, Jack.
传说领袖之路会通向那里
It is said the path of the Primes' leads there.
我们肯定很接近了
We must be close.
魔力神球…在下面？
Vector Sigma is... down here?
卡隆也不是一直都属于霸天虎
Kaon didn't always belong to the Decepticons.
威震天把它当做首都
Megatron took it as a capital.
显然他们没发现脚下藏着什么
Apparently without ever realising what lay beneath their feet.
阿尔茜！
Arcee!
我们正遭到某种…
We are being attacked by some kind of...
…巨型甲虫的攻击！
giant bot-beetle!
一个机器昆虫！
An Insecticon!
一个什么？
A what?
霸天虎在塞博特恩做什么？
What are Decepticons doing on Cybertron?
有几个留下来的 休眠在此
A few remained in stasis.
是看家的 以防止敌人突然造访
Sentries, should the enemy return.
杰克！走！
Jack! Go!
你当真吗？
Seriously?
离开阿尔茜？她是他的向导！
Without Arcee? She's his guide!
不 达比护士 阿尔茜是杰克的后援
No, nurse Darby, Arcee is Jack's backup.
钥匙芯片才是他的向导
The Key-Card is his guide.
快走啊！
Do it!
听她的 杰克
Listen to her, Jack.
你已经走到这一步了 擎天柱还指望着你呢
You've made it this far. Optimus is counting on you.
明白 妈妈
Roger that, Mom.
奥利安！
Orion!
你的“铁堡”计划有进展吗？
Have you made progess with project "Iacon"?
看起来我比想象的还要笨
It seems I am a bit rustier than I thought.
那是否和你喜欢做课外研究的天性有关？
Might that have anything to do with the nature of your after-hours research?
我是不是没提过我们会追踪你的动向？
Did I fail to mention that we would be tracking your activities?
为什么历史描绘中我跟汽车人的匪首是同一阵营？
Why does history portray me siding with the Autobot aggressors?
还有红蜘蛛为什么称我为领袖？
And why did Starscream call me a Prime?
我必须知道！
I must know!
我是谁？
Who am I?
你是我的手下
You are my clerk.
现在回去工作然后把数据库破译出来
Now get back to work and decode that database.
…不
... No.
我宁可把我的发现都删掉
I would rather erase my findings
也不给你拿去胡作非为
than make them available for your questionable use.
你真的以为我们没有追踪和记录\N你那些珍贵研究的点点滴滴吗？
Did you really think that we wouldn't be tracking and documenting every iota of your invaluable research?
我们留在塞博特恩的一个哨兵被激活了？
One of our sentries was activated, on Cybertron?
你跟我说我们的星球已经死了
You told me our planet was dead.
那不是重点 来人！
That is beside the point. Guards!
在我回来之前你就得完成“铁堡”计划
You will finish project "Iacon" by the time I return
否则我就让你亲眼看着我挖出你的火种！
or I will carve out your Spark before your very eyes!
活动记录显示我的太空桥定向到了塞博特恩…
The activity log indicates my Space-bridge was set for Cybertron...
…而且一直开着？
... and remains open?
汽车人如此大胆的冒险只有一个原因
The only possible reason the Autobots would take such a risk...
…为了让他们的宝贝擎天柱复原
... would be to restore their precious Optimus Prime.
各位 我进来了！
Hey everyone! I'm in.
太好了！
Sweet!
这就是…哇哦
This is... Wow.
开始下载了…我猜
Commencing download. ... I think.
就快了 擎天柱
Soon, Optimus.
没人让你停下来 派克斯
No one told you to stop, Pax.
我相信威震天打算用“铁堡”计划的\N成果来对付汽车人
I believe Megatron intends to use whatever he finds in project "Iacon" to harm the Autobots.
求你们了 我们得警告他们
Please. We can warn them.
这需要时间
This is taking awhile.
这是当然
Of course it is.
这可是历代领袖的智慧结晶
We are talking about the collective wisdom of the Primes.
怎么了 杰克？
What is it, Jack?
吸屑虫
Scraplets!
吸屑虫是什么？
What's a scraplet?
为什么偏偏是吸屑虫！
Why did it have to be scraplets?!
如果它们在领导模块完全重启之前咬穿魔力神球…
If they chew through Vector Sigma before the Matrix fully reloads...
那么说…魔力神球并不只是传说
So Vector Sigma is more than legend.
你们汽车人拯救首领的举动真是令人印象深刻
You Autobots have gone to impressive lengths to recover your Leader.
请相信…我决不会再低估你们了
Be assured, I shall never underestimate you again.
现在… 我猜那个叫阿尔茜的\N正拿着重启的领导模块从那个隧道中走过来
Now... I assume the one called Arcee will be stepping through that portal with the reloaded Matrix of Leadership in hand.
我们得不惜一切代价守住太空桥！
We hold the Space-bridge at all costs!
给我滚下去 铁桶头！
You're going down, Bucket-head!
杰克？
Jack?
哦 不 不 现在可别失灵！
Oh no-no-no-no, don't quit now!
阿尔茜？
Arcee?
给我退回去 虫子！
Back off, bug!
嘿 伙计们 主菜来了！
Hey, guys! The main course!
领导模块搞定！
I have the Matrix.
我们快走
Let's roll.
你必须承认
You have to admit
践踏汽车人的前任领袖也让人倍感殊荣
it's a privilege to stomp the former leader of the Autobots.
别 请…住手
No, please... stop.
够了！
Enough!
我…有武器？
I'm... armed?
我们就快到了
We're almost there.
救护车 我们搞定了领导模块
Ratchet, we have the Matrix.
我们正赶过来
We're coming through.
救护车？
Ratchet?
有点不对劲
Something's wrong.
我们无论如何也得过去 不是吗？
We can’t... not go through, can we?
来啊 阿尔茜
Come, Arcee.
来让我终结这领袖的传承
So that I might end the lineage of the Primes for all time.
我决不允许 威震天
I cannot allow that to happen, Megatron.
你这是狗拿耗子 奥利安・派克斯
And why should you care, Orion Pax?
你又不是领袖
You are no Prime.
也许这是事实 也许又是另一个谎言？
That may be true. Or yet another deception?
不过有一点我很明白：
But this much I do know:
我对汽车人有认同感 而你不是我们当中的一员
my sympathies lie with the Autobots and you are not one of us.
也许你的火种真的找准了位置 奥利安
Your Spark may be in the right place, Orion.
不过你要是想跟我过招 那还早着呢
But you have much to learn before you can hope to ever again stand your ground against me.
很遗憾 那一天不会来临的
A moment, sadly, which shall never come.
你…确定我配得上？
Are you... certain I am worthy?
你不了解自己的伟大
You have no idea.
很高兴你能加入这温馨的大团圆
How nice of you to join our little reunion.
现在 你可否交出…
Now, if you please...
领导模块？！
the Matrix?!
不！
Noo!
威震天…
Megatron...
退下！
Be gone!
救护车！我们怎么会来到这里？
Ratchet! How did we arrive here?
说来话长 老朋友
Long story, old friend.
基地呼叫阿尔茜！
Base to Arcee!
我们检测到下面有五个汽车人的生命信号
We're reading five Autobot life signals down there.
擎天柱跟你们在一起吗？
Is Prime with you?
还有杰克
And Jack.
好哎！
Yes!
啊！
Ah!
是接我们的！
It's ours!
汽车人 返回基地！
Autobots, fall back!
这一次 他可不会跟你走了！
This time he's coming with us.
杰克！
Jack!
擎天柱？
Optimus?
你好 拉斐尔
Hello, Rafael.
- 哇！\N- 老大记起咱们了！
- Woah.\N- The Big Guy remembers us! Woo-hoo!
虽然好像有些事情我记不起来了
Although it seems there is much I do not remember.
擎天柱 我们度过了最黑暗的时刻
Optimus. It has truly been our darkest hour.
但同时
But know this:
种种迹象表明 你的火种
from every indication your Spark
从未抛弃过汽车人的理想
never ceased being that of an Autobot.